<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>A Day Without Chocolate</title>
    <link>http://blog.hardikr.com</link>
    <language>en</language>
    <webMaster>me@hardikr.com (Hardik Ruparel)</webMaster>
    <pubDate>2011-03-07T01:36:31+04:00</pubDate>
    <copyright>Copyright 2011</copyright>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <description>A Blog by Hardik Ruparel</description>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egypt, India</title>
      <link>http://blog.hardikr.com/india/egypt-india</link>
      <pubDate>Tue Mar 01 00:00:00 +0400 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.hardikr.com/india/egypt-india/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping in tune with my last post about &lt;a href='http://blog.hardikr.com/post/3196114018/call-me'&gt;verbs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;pulling off an ‘Egypt’&lt;/em&gt; seems like a acceptable phrase that India can aspire to. Let’s take a look at some of the causes of the Egyptian Revolution of 2011. Let’s stack up Egypt’s problems alongside India’s (with utmost respect towards Egypt, I know it was much worse off than India is now, but just for the sake or argument). According to Wikipedia,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;…over a million people were protesting to demand the overthrow of the Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak, an end to corruption and police repression, and democratic reforms of the political system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corruption: ✓&lt;br /&gt;Police Repression: ✓&lt;br /&gt;Democratic Reforms Required: ✓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grievances of Egyptian protesters have focused on legal and political issues including police brutality, state of emergency laws, lack of free elections and freedom of speech, and uncontrollable corruption, as well as economic issues including high unemployment, food price inflation, and low minimum wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legal and political issues: ✓&lt;br /&gt;Police Brutality: ✓&lt;br /&gt;State of Emergency Laws: x&lt;br /&gt;Lack of Free Elections: ✓ (Most of the members of parliament just inherit the posts from the previous generations of their family. I would hardly call that free elections.)&lt;br /&gt;Lack of Freedom of Speech: ✓&lt;br /&gt;Uncontrollable Corruption: ✓&lt;br /&gt;High Unemployment: - (Admittedly, India did decently well to control the effect of the recession.)&lt;br /&gt;Food Price Inflation: ✓&lt;br /&gt;Low Minimum Wages: ✓&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, India has a lot of things going for it when the leaders claim that the inflation rate is a sign of economic growth. I don’t buy it, however. And Economics Nobel Laureate Amartya Sen doesn’t either, who was Johnny-on-the-spot &lt;a href='http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5hPEP4v8X3uqX4vQ-KSlAVXxbqY0A?docId=CNG.26f85a77fe573d0130a10eb475c1a65e.c41'&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen argued that New Delhi was far behind in the growth race, but more importantly it lagged in other criteria that showed real living standards were far inferior in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life expectancy at birth in China was 73.5 years compared with 64.4 years in India; Infant mortality rate is 50 per thousand in India and just 17 in China, and the under-five mortality rate is 66 for Indians and 19 for the Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China’s adult literacy rate is 94 percent, compared with India’s 65 percent, and mean years of schooling in India is 4.4 years, compared with 7.5 years in China, he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Almost half of our children are undernourished compared with a very tiny proportion in China,” Sen added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it’s not just me who agrees that this obsession of thinking that India is actually growing is unhealthy, unfounded and unfair to the middle and lower class, who pay taxes and die respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve said it over and over again, when a country cannot stop it’s children from dying, that means something’s wrong. While we’re spending millions on our defense research to launch &lt;a href='http://news.google.co.in/news/url?sa=t&amp;amp;ct2=in/0_0_s_0_0_t&amp;amp;ct3=MAA4AEgAUABgAWoCaW4&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGwSh9GKChv4xi-cOLtqmY8CMYjfw&amp;amp;cid=8797660069560&amp;amp;ei=rohbTaCbK8G3cKXNzN0C&amp;amp;rt=SEARCH&amp;amp;vm=STANDARD&amp;amp;url=http://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/india/DRDO-develops-mosquito-repellent-cream/articleshow/7496555.cms'&gt;mosquito repellent creams&lt;/a&gt;, more than 2.35 million under the age of five &lt;a href='http://www.reuters.com/article/2010/11/13/us-india-deaths-child-idUSTRE6AC01Y20101113'&gt;die&lt;/a&gt; every year (60% of them from easily avoidable causes.) Does &lt;em&gt;anybody else&lt;/em&gt; see a problem here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s see, what options do we have to set things right? I’m actually at a loss of words when I think about the arduous process to get anything done from the government of India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s pull of an Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://blog.hardikr.com/tag/india">india</category>
      
      <category domain="http://blog.hardikr.com/tag/egypt">egypt</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call Me, or How Becoiming a Verb is a Sign of Success</title>
      <link>http://blog.hardikr.com/startups/call-me</link>
      <pubDate>Wed Feb 09 00:00:00 +0400 2011</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.hardikr.com/startups/call-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever noticed, many of the successful technologies that have emerged over the past century, have become verbs of their own right, or become the de-facto ‘direct object’ of an &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Verb#Valency'&gt;intransitive verb&lt;/a&gt;. First we have some of the golden oldies,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Call me&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Fax me&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;E-mail me&amp;#8221; / &amp;#8220;Check my e-mail&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Watching TV&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Digg it&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And today, some new players that have turned proper nouns into verbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;Chatting with ..&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Google it&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Facebook me&amp;#8221; / &amp;#8220;Surfing Facebook&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Tweet me&amp;#8221; / &amp;#8220;TweetUp&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Dropbox the file&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Instapaper it&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Reddit it&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8220;Radbox it&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verbs have this strange force about them. There’s an inherent sense of authority/action about them that tends to catch on. A psycholinguist would definitely be in a better position to explain, if and why, verbs are words of power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, some technologies/products are almost incapable of becoming a verb, say the iPhone, and it obviously doesn’t make it any less of a success story. But, this is just something interesting to keep in mind while marketing your product !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: I write this as a marketing layman. So, don’t blame me if you market your startup as a verb and it doesn’t work out ;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
      <category domain="http://blog.hardikr.com/tag/startups,products">startups,products</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
